(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-10T16:36:45.305042",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
よみがえれ
Revive...
空と大地が 交差している
The sky and the earth are crossing paths,
今たたずんでる この世界で
in this world where I stand right now.
命が生まれ また沈んでく
Life is born and then fades away,
繰り返される 営みの中
within the endless flow of life.
こんなもんと よぎった瞬間
When I thought, "This is just how it is,"
夢は力をなくす
dreams lose their power.
もう一度 生まれよう
Let's be born once more,
この場所で
right here in this place.
正義のその奥で 夢が息づいている
Deep within justice, dreams are breathing alive.
重なる力を信じて
Believing in the power that we share,
正義のその奥に 闇が潜んでいる
deep within justice, darkness is lurking.
見極めろ 全てを
See it all clearly!
振り上げた勇気は 切り裂くためじゃない
The courage we raised isn't meant to tear apart,
引き合う絆で
but with the bonds drawing us together,
呼び覚ませ 鮮やかに
vividly awakening!
傷ついて 行き場をなくし
Wounded and losing our place to go,
さまよっている その魂を
that wandering soul...
癒す力は 心の奥で
The power to heal is deep within the heart,
静かに鼓動を刻んでいる
quietly beating away.
持てる力 全てぶつけ 涙を流すのなら
If you're going to put all your strength into it and shed tears,
選ぶべき道は 君を待っている
the path you should choose is waiting for you.
見失った今と 通り過ぎた過去
Between the lost present and the passing past,
狭間で諦めるよりも
rather than giving up in despair,
今目をそらさずに ここから始めよう
let's start fresh from here without looking away.
見極めろ 明日を
See tomorrow clearly!
誰かに見せ付ける 勇気は脱ぎ捨てて
Cast off the courage meant to show off to others,
素顔に戻ろう
and return to your true self.
呼び覚ませ 鮮やかに
Vividly awakening!
正義のその奥で 夢が息づいている
Deep within justice, dreams are breathing alive.
重なる力を信じて
Believing in the power that we share,
正義のその奥に 闇が潜んでいる
deep within justice, darkness is lurking.
見極めろ 全てを
See it all clearly!
振り上げた勇気は 切り裂くためじゃない
The courage we raised isn't meant to tear apart,
引き合う絆で
but with the bonds drawing us together,
呼び覚ませ 鮮やかに
vividly awakening!
はーい！みなさん、こんかた！
Hi everyone, Konkata!
かなたそと神曲アニソンFes!!へようこそいらっしゃいました！
Welcome to Kanataso's God-tier Anison Fes!!
イェーイ、ありがとー！ありがとー！
Yay, thank you! Thank you!
はい、ということでハッシュタグは#天音かなた誕祭2024でいっぱい呟いてください！
So please tweet a lot using the hashtag #AmaneKanataBirthday2024!
ワンモアで！がんばるで！みんなもがんばってね！いっぱい呟いてね！
One more time! Do your best! Everyone do your best too! Tweet a lot!
ということで本日お客さん入ってます！どうぞー！
So today we have an audience here! Tada!
うぱおだー！みなさん知ってますか、うぱおという存在を。
It's Upao! Do you all know the existence of Upao?
え、みんなじゃなきゃね、ちょっと認知度が低く、あんまりグッズも売れてないんですけども
Well, if it's not you guys, its recognition is a bit low, and not much merchandise sells, but...
そんなこと言ったらみんなに愛されるキャラになりました！よかったね、うぱお。
after saying things like that, it became a character loved by everyone! Good for you, Upao.
うぱお役もやりつつ、本日頑張っていこうと思います。たくさんのうぱおに囲まれて歌っていきます！
While playing the role of Upao, I'll do my best today. I'll sing surrounded by lots of Upaos!
それでは早速次の曲まいりましょう！いくぞー！
Now then, let's move on to the next song! Here we go!
みんなもっともっと盛り上がれますかー！
Can everyone get even more hyped up?!
さっそく、もうゲストがが登場します！
Now, our guest is appearing!
トップバッターはフレアです、どうぞー！
Our top batter is Flare, go ahead!
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
Fire away! The dreams in your heart
未来さえ置き去りにして
Leaving even the future behind
限界なんて知らない 意味ない！
It knows no limits and has no meaning!
この能力が光散らす その先に遥かな想いを
My power radiates these distant feelings ahead
歩いてきたこの道を 振り返ることしか
If I can only look back on this path I've walked
出来ないなら…今ここで全てを壊せる
I could destroy it all here and now...
暗闇に落ちる街並み 人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
Streets in darkness, how far can people resist?
加速するその痛みから 誰かをきっと守れるよ
I'm sure I can protect someone from this accelerating pain
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it right now
身体中を 光の速さで 駆け巡った 確かな予感
A certain premonition running through my body at light speed
掴め！望むものなら残さず 輝ける自分らしさで
Catch it! Don't leave your wishes behind with your shining self
信じてるよ あの日の誓いを
I believe in the vow we made that day
この瞳に光る涙 それさえも強さに変わるから
Even the tears shining in these eyes will turn into strength
立ち止まると 少しだけ 感じる切なさに 戸惑うことないなんて嘘をつかないよ
Stopping for a moment, feeling a slight sorrow—I won't lie and say I don't hesitate
宙に舞うコインが描く 放物線が決める運命
The parabola drawn by the coin dancing in the air determines our fate
打ち出した答えが今日も 私の胸を駆け巡る
The answer I fired out rushes through my chest again today
Sparkling! The shiny lights awake true desire.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 必ず
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it without fail
貫いてく 迷うことなく 傷ついても 走り続ける
Piercing through without hesitation, keeping on running even if hurt
狙え！凛と煌く視線は 狂い無く闇を切り裂く
Aim! The dignified and glittering gaze cuts through the darkness without fail
迷いなんて吹き飛ばせばいい
Just blow away any hesitation
この心が叫ぶ限り 誰ひとり邪魔などさせない
As long as this heart screams, I won't let anyone get in the way
儚く舞う無数の願いは この両手に積もってゆく
Countless transient wishes dance and pile up in these hands
切り裂く闇に見えてくるのは 重く深く切ない記憶
Cutting through the darkness comes heavy, deep, painful memories
色褪せてく現実に揺れる 絶望には負けたくない
Trembling in a fading reality, I don't want to yield to despair
私が今 私であることを 胸を張って 全て誇れる!
I will puff out my chest and be proud that I am myself right now!
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it.
今すぐ 身体中を 光の速さで 駆け巡った 確かな 予感
A certain premonition that ran through my body at the speed of light right now
掴め! 望むものなら残さず 輝ける自分らしさで
Catch it! If it's your wish, don't leave anything behind, with your shining individuality
信じてるよ あの日の誓いを
I believe in the vow of that day
この瞳に光る涙 それさえも強さになるから
Even the tears shining in these eyes will become strength
立ち止まるとなんだか少しだけ感じる切なさに 戸惑う事ないなんて嘘はつけないよ
Standing still, I feel a slight pain; I can't lie and say I'm not confused at all
穹舞うコインが描く 放物線が決める運命
The parabola drawn by the coin dancing in the sky decides our fate
打ち出した答えが今日も 私の胸を駆け巡る
The answer I shot out rushes through my heart again today
Sparkling! The shiny lights awake true desire.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it.
素晴らしき世界に今日も乾杯
A toast today as well to this wonderful world
街に飛び交う笑い声も
Even the laughter echoing through the town
見て見ぬふりしてるだけの作りもんさ
Are just manufactured things turning a blind eye
気付け触れそうだ
I feel like I'm losing my mind
クラクラするほどの良い匂いが
A sweet scent so intoxicating
ツンと刺した鼻の奥
Pierces sharply deep inside my nose
目を覚ます本能のまま今日は誰の番だ
Following my awakening instincts, whose turn is it today?
この世界で何ができるのか
What can I do in this world?
僕には何ができるのか
What can I do?
ただその真っ黒な目から 涙零れ落ちないように
Just so tears won't overflow from those pitch-black eyes of mine
願う未来に何度でもずっと 喰らい付く
No matter how many times, I will bite down onto the future I wish for
この間違いだらけの世界の中
In this world full of mistakes
君には笑ってほしいから
Because I want you to smile
もう誰も傷付けない 強く強くなりたいんだよ
I won't hurt anyone anymore, I want to grow stronger, stronger
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can remain myself
素晴らしき世界は今日も安泰
Today as well, this wonderful world is safe
街に渦巻く悪い話も
Bad rumors swirling around the town
知らない知らないふりして目を逸らした
I acted like I didn't know, turning my gaze away
正気の沙汰じゃないな 真面目に着飾った行進
It's sheer madness, a procession dressed up seriously
鳴らす足音が弾む行き先は
The destination of the bouncing footsteps is ringing
消えない消えない味が染み付いている 裏側の世界
The taste that never fades is stained within, the world on the other side
清く正しく生きること 誰も悲しませずに生きること
To live purely and righteously, to live without making anyone sad
はみ出さず真っ直ぐに生きること それが間違いしないで生きること
To live straight without stepping out of bounds, to live without any mistakes
ありのまま生きることが正義か 騙し騙し生きるのは正解か
Is living just as you are justice? Is living deceitfully the correct answer?
僕のあるべき姿と離れた 本当の僕は小魚なんだ 教えてくれよ
Diverging from the way I should be, the real me is just a small fry. Please tell me!
今日も答えのない世界の中で 願ってるんだよ
Still wishing within this world with no answers today as well
不器用だけれド いつまでも君とただ笑っていたいから
Even though I'm clumsy, because I just want to laugh with you forever
跳ねる心臓が身体揺らし叫ぶんだよ 今こそ動き出せ!
My beating heart shakes my body and screams, now is the time to make a move!
弱い自分を何度でもずっと 喰らい付く
No matter how many times, I will bite down onto my weak self
この間違いだらけの世界の中 君には笑ってほしいから
In this world full of mistakes, because I want you to smile
もう誰も傷付けない 強く強くなりたいんだよ
I won't hurt anyone anymore, I want to grow stronger, stronger
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can remain myself
ただ君を守るそのために 走る走る走るんだよ 僕の中の僕を超える
Just to protect you, I'll run, run, run, surpassing the me inside of me!
まるでお伽の話 終わり迎えた証
Many days tinted in fairy tale scenes, arrived at the end, proof we have seen
長過ぎる旅路から切り出した一節
I cut out and choose from a trip so long a little passage
まるで御伽の話
Like a fairy tale,
終わり迎えた証
the proof it reached its end.
長過ぎる旅路から切り出した一節
A fragment carved from a journey far too long.
それはかつてこの地に影を落とした悪を
This was once the evil that cast its shadow upon this land,
討ち取りし勇者との短い旅の記憶
memories of a short journey with the hero who defeated it.
物語は終わり
The story is over,
勇者は眠りにつく
and the hero goes to sleep.
穏やかな日常を
A peaceful everyday life
この地に残して
left behind in this land.
時の流れは無情に
The flow of time, mercilessly,
人を忘れさせる
makes people forget.
そこに生きた軌跡も錆び付いていく
Even the traces of life lived there are rusting away.
それでも君の
Even so, your words,
言葉も願いも勇気も
your wishes, your courage,
今も確かに私の中で生きている
still live on securely inside me.
同じ道を選んだそれだけだったはずなのに
We chose the same path, or so it should have been, but—
いつの間にかどうして
before I knew it, why
頬を伝う涙の理由をもっと知りたいんだ
do tears stream down my cheeks? I want to know more.
今更だって共に歩んだ旅路を辿れば
Even now, if I retrace the journey we shared together,
そこに君は居なくともきっと見つけられる
even if you're no longer there, I'm sure I'll find it.
物語は続く
The story continues,
一人の旅へと発つ
as I set off on a journey alone.
立ち寄る街で出会う
In the towns I stop by,
人の記憶の中に残る君は
you, remaining in people's memories,
相も変わらずお人好しで
are as good-natured as ever,
格好つけてばっかりだね
always trying to look so cool.
あちらこちらに作ったシンボルは勝ち取った平和の証
The symbols made here and there are proof of the peace we won.
それすら未来でいつか私が一人にならないようにあの旅を思い出せるように残された目印
Even those were left behind so that one day in the future, I wouldn't be alone, so I could remember that journey.
まるで御伽の話
Like a fairy tale,
終わり迎えた証
the proof it reached its end.
私を変えた出会い 百分の一の旅路
An encounter that changed me, one percent of the journey.
君の勇気をいつか風がさらって誰の記憶から消えてしまっても
Even if the wind someday sweeps away your courage and it fades from everyone's memories,
私が未来に連れて行くから 君の手を取った
I will take you with me into the future, holding the hand
あの日全て始まった
of that day where it all began.
思わずふっと笑ってしまうようなありふれた時間が
Mundane times that make me suddenly chuckle
今も眩しい 知りたいんだ 今更だって
are still dazzling. I want to know, even now,
振り返るとそこにはいつでも 優しく微笑みかける君がいるから
because when I look back, you are always there, smiling gently.
新たな旅の始まりは 君が守り抜いたこの地に
The beginning of a new journey is in this land you protected to the end,
芽吹いた命と共に
alongside budding life.
大嫌いだったそばかすをちょっと ひと柄にしてタメ息をひとつ
I sighed a bit over the freckles I used to hate so much.
ヘビー級の恋はみごとに 角砂糖と一緒に溶けた
My heavyweight crush melted away nicely, along with a sugar cube.
前よりももっとやせた胸にちょっと “チクッ”とささるトゲが痛い
The thorn pricking my slightly thinner chest hurts.
星占いもあてにならないわ もっと遠くまで一緒に行けたら ねぇ うれしくて それだけで
Fortune-telling is no use either. If we could go even further together... Oh, just being happy about that
想い出は いつもキレイだけど
Memories are always so pretty,
それだけじゃ おなかがすくわ
but that alone doesn't satisfy my hunger.
本当は せつない夜なのに
Even though it's actually a painful night,
どうしてかしら? あの人の笑顔も思い出せないの
why is it? I can't even remember that person's smile.
想い出は いつもキレイだけど
Memories are always so pretty,
それだけじゃ おなかがすくわ
but that alone doesn't satisfy my hunger.
本当は せつない夜なのに
Even though it's actually a painful night,
どうしてかしら? あの人の笑顔も思い出せないの
why is it? I can't even remember that person's smile.
大キライだったそばかすをちょっと
I used to hate my freckles a little
人しれずしてタメ息をひとつ
and breathed a quiet sigh in secret.
ヘヴィー級の恋はみごとに
A heavy-class love so splendidly
角砂糖と一緒に溶けた
dissolved right along with the sugar cube.
前よりももっとやせた胸にちょっと
My chest, even thinner than before,
チクッと刺さるトゲがイタイ
hurts slightly from a sharp thorn pricking me.
星占いもあてにならないわ
Fortune-telling is of no use either.
もっと遠くまで一緒に行けたら　ねえ
If we could've gone even further together...
うれしくてそれだけで
Just that made me so happy,
想い出はいつもキレイだけど
memories are always beautiful, but
それだけじゃおなかがすくの
that alone won't satisfy my hunger.
本当は切ない夜なのに
Even though it's actually a painful night,
どうしてかしら？
why is it?
あの人の笑顔も思い出せないの
I can't even remember that person's smile.
こわしてなおしてわかってるのに
I know I should break and fix it,
それがあたしの性格だから
but that's just how my personality is.
もどかしい気持ちであやふやなままで
With these frustrating, vague feelings,
それでもいい恋をしてきた
I've still had some good romances.
おもいきり開けた左耳のピアスにはねえ
In the piercing of my fully opened left ear, you know...
笑えないエピソード
is an episode I can't even laugh about.
そばかすの数を数えてみる
I try counting the number of freckles.
汚れたぬいぐるみ抱いて
Hugging a dirty stuffed animal,
胸をさすトゲは消えないけど
the thorn piercing my chest won't go away, but
カエルちゃんもウサギちゃんも
even froggy and bunny
笑ってくれるの
will smile for me.
想い出はいつもキレイだけど
Memories are always beautiful, but
それだけじゃおなかがすくの
that alone won't satisfy my hunger.
本当は切ない夜なのに
Even though it's actually a painful night,
どうしてかしら？
why is it?
あの人の涙も思い出せないの
I can't even remember that person's tears.
思い出せないの
I can't remember...
どうしてなの？
Why is that?
笑ってくれるの
Will smile for me.
愚かでいいのだろう
Even if it's foolish,
見渡す夢の跡
gazing upon the ruins of dreams,
さよなら蒼き日々よ
farewell to those azure days.
Shangri-La
[Title: Shangri-La]
流れに身を任せ いつか大人になってゆく
Surrendering to the stream, eventually becoming an adult,
少しずつ汚れてゆく事なの？
is it a matter of becoming dirty little by little?
熟した果実だけ選ばれて
Only the ripe fruit is chosen,
ナイフで裂かれて呑み込まれる前に
and before being sliced with a knife and swallowed up,
僕らが目指したShangri-La
the Shangri-La we aimed for.
欲望は抑えきれずに 空想にまみれた
Unable to suppress our desires, we continued to seek
「自由」を求め続けた
"freedom" soaked in daydreams.
今なら言えるのだろう 此処がそう楽園さ
I can probably say it now, this place is indeed paradise.
さよなら蒼き日々よ
Farewell to those azure days.
大切な何かを 踏み台にしてまでも
Even if it means stepping on something precious...
一番高い林檎
the highest apple tree...
掴みたかった
I wanted to grab it.
無くしてから気付く 尊いモノ
Lost and then realized what is truly precious.
幼い僕等は 的はずれだらけさ
We, in our youth, were nothing but flawed.
満ち足りた日々の制圧は
The suppression of those fulfilled days...
情動不安定になる
makes our emotions unstable.
傷を負ってでも 羽ばたきたいと願うよ
Even with scars, I want to soar.
愚かでいいのだろう
Foolishness is fine.
見渡す夢の跡
Passing by the traces of dreams.
さよなら 蒼き日々よ
Farewell, those pale days.
輝く空は
The shining sky...
無邪気さを装い
feigned innocence,
全てを知っていた...
knowing everything...
僕等は目指した Shangri-La
We aimed for Shangri-La.
欲望は抑えきれずに
Unable to hold back our desires,
空想にまみれた
overflowing with daydreams,
「自由」を求め続けた
we kept searching for "freedom."
距離を置いてこそ
Leaving distance behind...
自分の大きさを知る
we learn our own magnitude.
未熟な心は
An immature heart...
それさえ分からないまま
cannot even understand that yet.
今なら言えるだろう 此処がそう楽園さ
Now I can say this is paradise.
さよなら 蒼き日々よ
Farewell, those pale days.
遥か空響いている
Echoing in the distant skies,
祈りは奇跡に
prayers become miracles.
このライブももう折り返しに来てます！
We have returned once more for this live show!
みんなまだまだ盛り上がっていけるよね！
Let's climb even higher together!
真夜中の蒼に溶けて
Dissolving into the blue of the deep night,
流れてく涙のつぶ
droplets of flowing tears
迷いなく包み込む温もりに出会った
met a warmth that embraced me without hesitation.
真っ白な雪のように どこまでも素直な言葉
Like pure white snow, with endlessly honest words,
鉄の羽根纏った 僕を動かしていく
the steel wings drove me forward.
傷つくたびに 優しくなれる
Every time I get hurt, I become kinder;
君のその笑顔だけ 守り抜きたい
I want to protect your smile alone.
願いはひとつ
I have only one wish.
時を越え刻まれた 悲しみの記憶
Memories of sorrow etched across time,
まっすぐに受け止める 君は光の女神
embraced straight on—you are the goddess of light.
あの日胸に灯った 永遠の炎
The eternal flame that lit my heart that day,
深い闇解き放って
releasing deep darkness,
自由のトビラ開いてく
opens the door to freedom,
強く果てない未来へ
toward a strong, unending future!
冷たい緑の月に 映し出す心の影
Reflecting in the cold green moon,
淋気に呟いた
murmuring with loneliness,
「君のそばにいたい」
"I want to be by your side."
遥か天空響いている
Echoing in distant skies,
祈りは奇跡に
Prayers turn to miracles.
真夜中の蒼に溶けて流れてゆく涙の粒
Flowing teardrops dissolving into the midnight blue,
迷いなく包み込む温もりに出逢った
I found a warmth that embraced me without hesitation.
真っ白な雪のように どこまでも素直なコトバ
Like pure white snow, words so honest and straightforward,
鉄の羽纏った
Wrapped in iron wings,
僕を動かしてゆく
driving me forward.
傷つくたびに優しくなれる
The more I'm hurt, the kinder I can become.
君のその笑顔だけ守り抜きたい 願いはひとつ
I want to protect only your smile, that is my single wish.
時空を超えて刻まれた悲しみの記憶 まっすぐに受け止める君は光の女神
Memories of sorrow etched across time, you who embrace them are the goddess of light.
あの日胸に灯った永遠の炎 深い闇解き放て 自由のトビラ開いてく
The eternal flame lit in my chest that day, unleashing deep darkness, opening the door to freedom,
強く果てない未来へ
toward a strong, endless future.
駆け上がる切なさに 生まれ行く誓い
To the surging heartbreak, a vow is born,
もう何も怖くはないよ
I am no longer afraid of anything.
結んだ視線 そらさずに
Without looking away from our joined gazes,
大切な「今」始める
Beginning the precious "now".
エターナル・ブレイズ
ETERNAL BLAZE
君と二人でいられる場所
A place where I can be with you,
まぼろしにさらわれないように
So that we aren't swept away by illusions,
消えない雨の苦しみも
Even the unending pain of the rain,
鍵を壊してぶつけてよ
Break the lock and smash it against me.
隣にいるから すべてを信じて
Because I am right beside you, believe in everything.
時空を超えて刻まれた 悲しみの記憶
Memories of sorrow etched across time,
まっすぐに受け止める 君は光の女神
You who embrace them straightaway are the goddess of light.
あの日胸に灯った 永遠の炎
The eternal flame lit in my chest that day,
深い闇解き放て 自由のトビラ開いてく
Unleashing deep darkness, opening the door to freedom,
強く果てない未来へ
Toward a strong, endless future.
そう、きっとここから始まる…
Yes, it surely begins right from here...
伝説の朝に誓った言葉
Words pledged on the morning of legend,
分かち合う声にきせきよ照らせ
Let miracles illuminate our sharing voices.
革命をLet's shout
Revolution, let's shout!
風の舞う光の空 吹き抜ける残響
The wind dances through the sky of light, echoes blowing through.
この右手とこの左手 何を求める？
This right hand and this left hand, what do they desire?
魂のカタルシスに焦がれた感情を重ねあわせば
If we layer emotions burning for the catharsis of the soul,
つなぎあえば 伝わるのか？
If we connect them, will it reach across?
運命にゆだね流れるままに 変わらないビジョンじゃ面白くない
Surrendering to fate as it flows, an unchanging vision isn't interesting.
沸騰させろ血のライン
Boil the line of blood into a fever.
交差するプラズマのように
Like intersecting plasma,
革命のデュアリズム さあ始めよう
Revolution's dualism, now let's begin!
以心伝神 生の叫び 届いていますか？
Telepathic heart-to-heart, the roar of life, is it reaching you?
化学反応 愛が伝承 ついて来い夢の果て
Chemical reaction, love handed down, follow me to the end of dreams!
どんなロードだって いつかは交り合う その日君はジャッジメントする
No matter what road it is, one day we will cross paths, and on that day you will pass judgment.
革命をLet's shout
Revolution, let's shout!
伝説の朝に誓った言葉
The words we swore on that legendary morning,
分かち合う声に行き先を照らせ
Let them illuminate our destination as our voices unite.
革命をLet's shout
Let's shout the revolution!
痛みを溶かして
Dissolving the pain,
何を守り 何を信じ 生きろと言う?
What must we protect, what believe in, telling us to live?
未来へのドアは コインのトスさ
The door to the future is a coin toss.
残酷を選べ 暁のキミ
Choose the cruelty, O you of the dawn.
虹のかかる 見たことない
An unprecedented, breathtaking view
絶景のフライト 教えてやる
Where rainbows span—I'll teach you that flight!
覚醒のデュアリズム さぁ飛び込もう
Let's awaken the dualism, let's dive in!
百花繚乱 青の衝動 火花を散らして
A hundred flowers blooming, blue impulse, scattering sparks,
胸のブレイブを叩く鼓動 どこまでいけるのか?
The heartbeat in my chest—just how far can we go?
変わらない何かで 何度口づけした?
How many times have we kissed with something unchanging?
そしてキミは また恋に出会う
And then, you will meet love once again.
Just trust my heart.
Just feel my heart, hold you.
誇り高き愛の結晶 握り締めたら 迎えに行くから…
Once you grasp the proud crystallization of love, I'll come to meet you...
刹那から一生さえ すべて見せてきた キミへのラブソング
From a fleeting moment to an entire lifetime, my love song to you!
(Break out! 鎖ちぎって 独立せよ)
Break out! Tear off the chains and become independent!
以心伝神 生の咆哮 とどいているですか?
Telepathy, the roar of raw voices—is it reaching you?
化学反応 愛が伝承 ついてこい夢の果て
Chemical reaction, love handed down, follow me to the end of a dream.
どんなロードだって いつかは交り合う
No matter what the road is, someday they will cross paths,
その日 キミはジャッジメントする
On that day, you will pass judgment!
革命をLet's shout
Let's shout the revolution!
Just trust my heart.
Just feel my heart, hold you.
誇り高き愛の結晶
The proud crystallization of love,
握り締めたら 迎えに行くから…
Once grasped, I'll come to meet you...
刹那から一生さえ すべて見せてきた キミへのラブソング
From a fleeting moment to an entire lifetime, my love song to you!
(Break out! 鎖ちぎって 独立せよ)
Break out! Tear off the chains and become independent!
以心伝神 生の咆哮
Telepathy, the roar of raw voices,
とどいているですか? 化学反応 愛が伝承
Is it reaching you? Chemical reaction, love handed down,
ついてこい夢の果て どんなロードだって
Follow me to the end of a dream, no matter what the road is,
いつかは交り合う その日 キミは
Someday they will cross paths, on that day you will...
ジャッジメントする 囲み目をほら
Pass judgment! Look at your lined eyes,
嘘じゃない ２人はジャッジメントする
It's no lie, the two of us will pass judgment!
囲めよレイション 囲めよレイション
Surround the ration, surround the ration!
佐賀… 佐賀…
Saga... Saga...
佐賀… Yeah…
Saga... Yeah...
佐賀事変
[Title: Saga Jihen]
チキラン チキラン チキラン チキラン！
Chi kiran, chi kiran, chi kiran, chi kiran!
ひとり真紅の口紅
I'm all alone in the dead of night,
塗り直した真夜中
Painting my lips with the brightest of reds,
今夜は来る 来ない? 乾いていく
Won't you come tonight? I'm drying up,
乱れ花びら散らして
Flower petals scattering left and right,
Ring dong… Ring dong…
Ring dong... Ring dong...
気儘ばらばらの理想 囚われの道化！
Your restraint will be gone just like that!
チキラン チキラン チキラン チキラン！
Chi kiran, chi kiran, chi kiran, chi kiran!
少し半端美人で
Have you heard of the flawless beauty
すぐに立つ噂
That can seduce anyone in an instant?
I wanna 墜落するなら
If you wanna taste the forbidden fruit,
その手で奪って！
Then take me with your hands!
How oah! How oah!
もう愛憎ぐるぐるコラヨウナ…
You're all pent up with love and hate, right?
Mayday! Mayday!
来なさい〜
Come on by~
殻脱ぎ捨て 私は挑みたい！
Reborn from my chrysalis, I want to tantalize!
束縛！ 束縛！ 束縛！ 束縛！
You're caught up in my web!
赤い鮮血で結ばれたい！
Connected by the red string of fate!
茨！ 茨！ 茨！ 茨！
On a thorny path!
三瀬峠、俵坂… 越えて！
Whether Mitsuse-toge or Tawarazaka...
地獄だって愛に来て！
Even in the depths of hell, come visit me!
風吹き気れ、霰、逃がれ…
Fight off strong winds, endure the hail...
来なさい〜！
And come on by!
チキラン チキラン チキラン チキラン！
Chi kiran, chi kiran, chi kiran, chi kiran!
ちゃん×ちゃん
Cha-cha!
逢！！チキチキバンバン
Meet!! Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
哀！？チキチキ バン バン
Alas!? Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
嗚呼！チキチキバンバン
Ah! Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
愛！！チュキチュキチュキ バンバン
Love!! Chuki Chuki Chuki Ban Ban
high チキチキバンバン
High, Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
哀！？チキチキ バン バン
Alas!? Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
嗚呼！チキチキバンバン
Ah! Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
愛！！チュキチュキ
Love!! Chuki Chuki
猫も杓子もみんな気まぐれで辛い
Everyone's so fickle, it's tough,
酔えばティーラ 有る無ル 幻想 連続でピーカン
Getting drunk on tequila, endless illusions, sunny skies.
夢はパンドラほら開きたくなる
Dreams are Pandora's box, making you want to open them.
みんな期待してパリピよ
Everyone expects it, party people!
今夜富士山昇りゃんにゃ分からない
Climbing Mount Fuji tonight, who knows?
決戦も週末の宿命
The decisive battle is the weekend's fate too.
ちゃん×ちゃん
Cha-cha!
逢！！チキチキバンバン
Meet!! Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
何も勿体振らず楽しめ fever tonight
Don't hold back, enjoy it, fever tonight!
ちゃん×ちゃん
Cha-cha!
哀！？チキチキバンバン！
Alas!? Chiki Chiki Ban Ban!
何度むしゃくしゃしたって party tonight
No matter how frustrated you get, party tonight!
ちゃん×ちゃん
Cha-cha!
嗚呼！チキチキバンバン
Ah! Chiki Chiki Ban Ban!
愚か者ほどhighとか言う完全社会
A perfect society where fools say "high" and such.
ちゃん×ちゃん
Cha-cha!
愛！！チキチキバンバン
Love!! Chiki Chiki Ban Ban!
みんなスーパースターの卵さ diva tonight
Everyone's a superstar in the making, diva tonight!
一筋のゲート あなたが越えて
Crossing a single gate that you surpassed,
地獄だって愛に抜けた
Even hell was pushed through with love.
猫も杓子も逃れられぬ運命
A fate no one can escape from,
死なないで狂おしい恋に揺られ
Don't die, swayed by a mad love.
甘い未来虎に
A sweet future like a tiger,
抱かれた手おぼれていい
It's okay to drown in those embraced hands.
チキランチキランチキラン
Chiki-ran, chiki-ran, chiki-ran!
かなたね、ルイちゃんでした！ありがとう！
It was Kanatane and Lui-chan! Thank you!
金時先輩お誕生日おめでとうございます！一緒に歌えて嬉しかったです！
Kintoki-senpai, happy birthday! We're so glad we could sing together!
ありがとう！またね～！
Thank you! See you later!
ありがとう、ありがとう、ありがとう...
Thank you, thank you, thank you...
はい！ということで、
Yes! And so,
え、あやめ先輩、あずきちゃん、そしてルイが来てくれました！ありがとう！
Ayame-senpai, Azuki-chan, and Lui came to join us! Thank you!
ということで、次の曲は、オリジナル曲を歌いたいと思います！
So, for the next song, I'd like to sing an original song!
今日はこのライブの後にアニメーションMVが投稿される！おーらくらー！
Today, after this live, an animated MV will be posted! Oracle!
みんな、まだまだ盛り上がっていきますよー！
Everyone, we're going to keep the hype going!
あともう少しでこのライブも終わってしまいます！
This live is coming to an end very soon!
最後まで全力出して盛り上がっていきまっしょい！
Let's give it our all and get hyped until the very end!
人、人、人で埋まったシャッター街に賑わってた過去は
In the shuttered shopping street filled with people, the bustling past...
ワン、ワン、ワンバク、ワンバク また追い込んじゃったんだ
Bark, bark, barking mad, chasing myself into a corner again.
チカ、チカって真っ赤な電飾 決壊を変えた誰か ブラン、ブラン運んでた いなくなっちゃった (あ〜あ)
Flickering red neon lights. Someone who changed the dam, swinging and carrying it away—they're gone. (Ah-ah)
カン、カンとカン、カン鳴ってた架空信号が勝ってたから
Because the imaginary signal clanging "clang, clang" was winning,
ガラ、ガラの終着駅 また突っ立っちゃってんだ？
At the empty terminal station, standing blankly once again?
フラ、フラと真っ平ら面相をやっちゃってないですか？
Aren't you making a totally deadpan face, swaying unsteadily?
あれ、あれ聞こえますか？それ吐き出しちゃいいますか？どうぞ！
Hey, can you hear it? Are you going to spew it out? Go ahead!
喧嘩ヒントちょうちょして ろくなしてビクなして あの日逃した 廃絶は自らの手で
Fusing fighting hints and butterflies, the ruin missed that day was by your own hands.
あれ、あれ噛み砕いてんだ 希薄になる根源的な良い子になるまで 愛してあげるね
Chewing it down until you become a fundamentally good child, getting thinner—I'll love you.
大丈夫、今度はよく満たしてぶっ殺すように恋をして、骨の髄まで、ちゃんと奥まで、ちゃんと愛、愛、愛 Love you!
Fill yourself well and love as if to kill, right to the marrow, right deep inside, properly love, love, love you!
涙より恋ごこち足りないままにバカになっちゃって 愛しいね かわいいね おめめに映すと
Remaining short on romantic feelings rather than tears, turning silly—how endearing, how cute, reflected in your eyes.
ざわざわが全部利息 君が隠し持ってた言葉なさずなでなでしてあげるから こっちおいでよ、ヨガ上手だね
The rustling is all interest. Since I'll gently pet the words you kept hidden, come over here, you're good at yoga, huh?
やるね 息が吸えたね 息が吐けたね ひとりだけで今日も仕事出来たね
Not bad! You were able to inhale, you were able to exhale, you managed to work all by yourself again today.
耳が上手ね 口が上手ね 泣いた顔も機嫌聞いちゃって
Good ears, good mouth, listening to your crying face's mood as well.
あぁ、君の存在から放たれた間違いの正しい有り得ないくらいもう愛して愛して堪らないんだけど自分1%にもならないからこれからも君の上からいくらでもいくらでもいくらでも注ぐからね
Released from your existence, there's no way a mistake could be right—I love you so much I can't bear it, but since you're not even 1% of yourself, from now on I'll pour over you endlessly!
しゃあないね しゃあないね 君のせいじゃないもんね
It can't be helped. It's not your fault, after all.
しゃあないね しゃあないね 寝寝したいよね もういいじゃん
It can't be helped. You want to sleep already, don't you? Enough is enough.
しゃあないね しゃあないね 泣いても泣いても来ないね
It can't be helped. Even if you cry and cry, they won't come.
しゃあないね しゃあないね 誰も返事しないもんね
It can't be helped. Nobody answers, after all.
あぁ、あれもうそんな傷つけたりしないで こんなめちゃくちゃだらけの世界に塗っちゃってごめんね 大丈夫 安全圏だよね
Don't hurt yourself like that anymore. Sorry for painting you in such a messy world. It's safe here, right?
安心の世界に行こうね 安らかな世界に行こうね
Let's go to a world of peace, let's go to a peaceful world.
一生ないからずっと今日も一緒にあぁ、あれもうそんな傷つけたりしないでこんなめちゃくちゃだらけの世界に眠っちゃってごめんね
Since there's no lifetime, always together today too... Ah, don't hurt yourself like that anymore, sorry for falling asleep in such a messy world.
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
Spoiler alert for love, a "breakup" vibe
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Spoiler alert for life, a "death" vibe
なにそれ意味深でかっこいいじゃん...
What's with that? So deep and cool...
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ 失礼
Dancing to a collection of buzzwords. Excuse me.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる 風
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu style
神っぽいな
It's so god-like
君が持ってきた漫画 くれた知らない名前の花
You brought me a manga and an unnamed flower
今日はまだ来ないかな? 初めての感情知ってしまった
Will you not come today? I've discovered a brand-new feeling
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって ひとりでに宇宙を旅して
Tracing the painting by the window, journeying through space alone
君の手を握ってしまったら 孤独を知らないこの街には
If I were to hold your hand, in this city that knows no loneliness,
もう二度と帰ってくることは
we could never return again...
君が手を差し伸べた 光で影が生まれる
You reached out your hand, and light created a shadow
歌って聞かせて この話の続き
Sing and let me hear the rest of this story
連れて行って 見たことない星まで
Take me to a star I've never seen before
誰の手も声も届かない 高く聳え立った塔の上へ
Above the towering spire where no hand or voice can reach
飛ばすフウセンカズラ 僕は君に笑って欲しいんだ
Flying balloon vine, I just want you to smile
満たされない穴は 惰性の会話や 澄ましたポーズで
Unfulfilled voids, with idle chatter and composed poses
これまでは埋めてきたけど
I've filled them up until now, but
退屈な日々を蹴散らして 君と二人で
Scattering these boring days, you and I together
この街中を泳いだら 素敵なことでしょう?
Swimming through this city, wouldn't that be wonderful?
出したことないほど 大きな声でやっと君に伝わる
Shouting louder than ever before, I finally reach you
歪なくらいがさ 世界の端と端を結んで
A slight distortion connects the ends of the world
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって ひとりでに宇宙を旅して
Tracing the painting by the window, journeying through space alone
それだけでも不自由だけど 僕は選んでみたいのさ
Even if it's confining, I want to choose it
高鳴る心 謎だらけの空を 安全なループを今 書き換えて
Rewrite this safe loop in a mysterious sky with a throbbing heart
君の手を握ってしまったら 孤独を知らないこの街には
If I were to hold your hand, in this city that knows no loneliness,
もう二度と帰ってくることはない
we could never return again...
いくらでも迷いながら 光も影も見に行こう
While getting lost however much, let's go see both light and shadow
歌って聞かせて この話の続き
Sing and let me hear the rest of this story
連れて行って 見たことない星まで
Take me to a star I've never seen before
誰の手も声も届かない 高く聳え立った塔の上へ
Above the towering spire where no hand or voice can reach
飛ばすフウセンカズラ 僕は君に笑って欲しいんだ
Flying balloon vine, I just want you to smile
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって ひとりでに宇宙を旅して
Tracing the painting by the window, journeying through space alone
それだけでも不自由だけど 僕は選んでみたいのさ
Even if it's confining, I want to choose it
高鳴る心 謎だらけの空を 安全なループを今 書き換えて
Rewrite this safe loop in a mysterious sky with a throbbing heart
君の手を握ってしまったら 孤独を知らないこの街には
If I were to hold your hand, in this city that knows no loneliness,
もう二度と帰ってくることはない
we could never return again...
いくらでも迷いながら 光も影も見に行こう
While getting lost however much, let's go see both light and shadow
歌って聞かせて この話の続き
Sing and let me hear the rest of this story
連れて行って 見たことない星まで
Take me to a star I've never seen before
誰の手も声も届かない 高く聳え立った塔の上へ
Above the towering spire where no hand or voice can reach
飛ばすフウセンカズラ 僕は君に笑って欲しいんだ
Flying balloon vine, I just want you to smile
歌って聞かせて この話の続き
Sing and let me hear the rest of this story
連れて行って 見たことない星まで
Take me to a star I've never seen before
誰の手も声も届かない 高く聳え立った塔の上へ
Above the towering spire where no hand or voice can reach
飛ばすフウセンカズラ 僕は君に笑って欲しいんだ
Flying balloon vine, I just want you to smile
ラストスパート！この5人でラストスパート駆け抜けてきました！
Final spurt! We've run through this final spurt together with the five of us!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ありがとー！
Thank you so much!
皆さん、天音かなた誕生日記念ライブどうでしたでしょうか？楽しんでいただけたでしょうか？
Everyone, how was Amane Kanata's birthday live? Did you enjoy it?
こちら誕生日記念2024グッズももちろん出ますと！
Of course, the 2024 birthday commemoration merch is also coming out!
こちらが誕生日記念のフルセットでございます、グッズフルセット。
This is the full birthday commemoration set, the merch full set.
えー、今後ね…今後じゃねえや、この後ね、あのね全部ね細かく紹介したいと思います が、
Um, going forward... no, not going forward, right after this, I'd like to introduce everything in detail, but
まず言いたいのは数量限定バージョンがございます！
first I want to say there is a quantity-limited version!
直筆サインが入ったもの、え、そして箔押し複製サインのメッセージ入りポストカードが入ったものとね、2種類ございます。よろしくお願いいたします！
There are two types: one with a handwritten signature, and one with a foil-stamped duplicate signature message postcard. Thank you!
え、そして、まずグッズです！アクリルパネル！こちらキラキラホログラム仕様ということで、キラキラ、光りますのでよろしくお願いいたします！
And first, the merch! Acrylic panel! This features a sparkling hologram design, so it shines bright, please check it out!
光るっていうのはこうなんかあのあれだから、角度変えたらキラキラ、光る感じ。
By shining, I mean, if you change the angle it just shines, that kind of feel.
あ、はい！ランダムステッカー！こちらあの全4種類からランダムに1枚封入されるランダムステッカーでございます！スマホの裏とかにねぜひ貼ってください。よろしくお願いいたします！
Ah, yes! Random sticker! This is a random sticker with one randomly included from all 4 types! Please stick it on the back of your smartphone. Thank you!
あ、こちらかなたちゃんぬいぐるみでございます！これねマジで超可愛いからあのぜひねいろんなところにおでかけ一緒に連れてってあげてください！
Ah, this is the Kanata-chan plushie! This is seriously super cute, so please take it out on adventures with you everywhere!
そしてそして、むにむに待らうばおキーホルダー！うぱおうがこれね完全でむにむにお待ちしております！本当にむにむにしてるんです！ぜひこのキーホルダーもね、あのなんか付けてくださいな！
And then, the Squishy Upaou Keychain! Upaou is completely waiting squishily here! It's genuinely squishy! Please attach this keychain too, somewhere!
はい、こちらがね全てのフルセットになっております！あのここでも単品でも買えますのでよろしくお願いいたしますね！はい、頑張ってサインも書かせていただきます！
Yes, this is the complete full set! You can also buy items individually here, so thank you! Yes, I'll do my best and sign them too!
そしてこの後は、アニメーションゲームMV、オラクルが投稿されます！よろしくお願いいたします！いやああのこちらねオリジナルの曲でございます！じんさんに作詞作曲していただきました！
And after this, the animation game MV 'Oracle' will be posted! Thank you! Yeah, um, this is an original song! Jin-san wrote the lyrics and music for us!
人、人、人で作った
Built by people, people, people,
シャッター街 賑わってた
the shuttered shopping street was bustling.
不安、不安、不安ばっか
Just anxiety, anxiety, anxiety,
まだ追い込んじゃったんだ？
did you push yourself into a corner again?
赤な電灯
A red electric light.
取って代わった 誰か
Someone who took over.
いなくなっちゃった
They disappeared.
あ、あ
Ah, ah.